

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BIOINFORMATICS

2225 Lamley St, Baltimore, MD, 21231

© (520)331-8386 | ■ ajstangl@gmail.com | • AJStangl

Summary.

Bioinformatics Software Engineer with 3+ with years experience developing NGS analytical pipelines to identify genomic variants. Lead the development of two analytical pipeline for use by pharmaceutical partners in under one year. Highly proficient in multiple compiled and interpreted languages, work flow management systems, and formal design processes.

Technical Skills

Python, Perl, R, Java, C, PSQL/SQL, JavaScript, LaTeX **Programming Languages**

CyberInfastructure AWS, High-Throughput Computing, Unix, Ansible, Debian Package Manegment, TIGR Workflow,

Makeflow, Jinja, Sungrid Engine

Software Development and Lifecycle

BioInformatic Frameworks

Git and Version Control, JIRA, Agile/Scrum, Iterative Waterfall, Confluence, Sharepoint, Smartsheets Pandas/Numpy/Scipy, Matplotlib/Seaborn, Bioconductor, Plotly, Spotfire, RESTful API, Machine

Learning, Data Mining, Excel

Genomic Technologies Illumina HighSeq/NextSeq Platforms, Ion Torrent Sequencing, ,Protein Microarray, DNA Microarray,

Transcriptomics, IHC/In-Situ Hybridization

Bioinformatics Tools Samtools, Picard, BWA, BT2, NovoAlign, BLAST, MAFFT, PySam

Experience

Personal Genome Diagnostics

Baltimore, MD

BIOINFORMATICS SOFTWARE ENGINEER, I Oct. 2017 - PRESENT

- TODO
- TODO
- TODO

Personal Genome Diagnostics

GRADUATE INTERN - COMPARATIVE GENOMICS LAB

Baltimore, MD

ASSOCIATE ENGINEER Feb. 2016 - Oct. 2017

- TODO
- TODO
- TODO

University of Arizona

Tucson, Arizona Feb. 2015 - Jan 2016

Developed python programs for data mining and integration to internal genomic databases via RESTful API

- · Interpreted NGS genomic data from external sources and validated results with different alignment software
- · Communicated bugs and root cause of failures to lead software developer for resolution

Sanofi

Oro Valley, Arizona May. 2016 - August 2016

BIOLOGY INTERN - DRUG DISCOVERY

- Introduced methods of analysis that automated analysis of protien microarray data using R, Perl, and VBS for Excel
- Analyzed results of multiple small molucule targets across multiple projects and teams
- · Presented findings to project teams and communicated next steps for assay application

Tucson, Arizona

University of Arizona GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT Aug. 2015 - Dec 2015

- TODO
- TODO
- TODO

University of Arizona Undergraduate Laboratory Technician

Tucson, Arizona

Jun. 2013 - Aug 2014

- TODO
- TODO
- TODO

Education

University of Arizona Tucson, AZ

PROFESSIONAL SCIENCE MASTERS IN APPLIED BIOSCIENCES

May. 2016

- Focus: Bioinformatics, Data and Genomic Analysis, and Scientific Computing
- Thesis: Protein MicroArray Mediated Target Identification
- GPA: 4.0

University of Arizona Tucson, AZ

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MOLECULAR AND CELLULAR BIOLOGY

May. 2016

- · Focus: Bioinformatics, Biochemistry, and Laboratory Research
- GPA: 3.6
- Cum Laude

Presentation

University of Arizona Graduate College Graduate Reseach Exhibition

Tucson, AZ

PRESENTER FOR PROTEIN MICROARRAY MEDIATED IDENTIFICATION OF PHOSPHOHISTIDINE IN THE HUMAN PROTEOME

Dec 2015

• Introduced the use, analysis, and utility of protein microarrays for novel detection of binding site in the human proteome.

Arizona Bio Expo Scottsdale, Arizona

PRESENTER FOR < IRREGULAR PERIODICITY IN INSECT SEGMENTATION AND CRUSTACEAN TRANSCRIPTOMICS.>

Jun 2014

• Introduced the application of NGS Transcriptomics for the identification of uncharacterized genes in non-model organisms.